# Ryan Brady

101 Russell Blvd Davis, CA. 95616 | rpbrady@ucdavis.edu | 949-276-1773

## **PROFILE**

Third year Statistics major with experience in programming and statistical analysis. In-depth knowledge of logistic regression, linear regression, time series analysis, probability theory, geo-spatial analysis, and statistical learning techniques. Interested in applying statistical methods to create data frames to find solutions to intricate problems.

## **EDUCATION**

## University of California Davis, CA

June 2018 (expected)

Studying: Statistics and Political Science

## San Juan Hills High School, CA

**June 2014** 

Statistics GPA: 3.3

AP Scholar with Distinction

AP Tests with Score of 5: Macroeconomics, U.S. Government, U.S. History

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Data Mining - Craigslist Car Listings**

Dec. 2016

- Worked autonomously utilizing text string analysis to construct a CSV spreadsheet of relevant information about cars and their dealerships.
- CSV file further analyzed statistical data to form models assisting prediction of variables such as prices and vehicle models.
- Received an exceptional grade from the professor for robustness of the CSV and data analysis.

## **2016 Election Analysis**

Dec. 2016

- Coordinated with a group to analyze poverty and education rates in the United States against voter patterns in the presidential election.
- Employed Selenium, a program which allows the user to drive a browser through R, to web scrape dynamic web pages.
- Created data frame to map United States counties, highlighting voter data in a multi-colored visual for future statistical analysis. (I have attached this project in additional documents.)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Research Assistant Political Science Department at University of California

Dec 2016 - Present

- Worked under Professor Bradford Jones to better understand the multicollinearity relationships between political ideologies.
- Tasked with creating a codebook for surveyed data

#### **UC Davis Coffee House**

Sept. 2016 - Nov. 2016

- Collaborated with cross-functional student teams for kitchen prep and cooking at largest student run kitchen on campus.
- Worked 15hrs/week in fast paced, high pressure kitchen environment.

## **LEADERSHIP**

## **High School Class President**

June 2011- June 2013

- Improved school environment for the student body through creation and organization of school events that led to record turnout.
- Formed a budget plan where each future senior class would designate funds for school infrastructure projects.

## TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

- R Programming Language
- Python (Beginner), Pandas

- Microsoft Office
- Web APIS